我们这就叫自由集会
This is what the freedom to assemble looks like!
停止操纵媒体
Stop silencing the press!
停止迫害异己
Stop persecuting the opposition!
停止关押同性恋人士
Stop imprisoning people simply because they're gay!
你是在毁掉俄罗斯的未来
You're destroying Russia's future!
佩特罗夫的车队来了之后
When Petrov's motorcade arrives,
让军乐队使劲大声演奏
have the band already playing as loud as they can.
我跟上校说一下
I'll speak to the Colonel.
-暴动小猫的姑娘呢  -我亲自跟她们交待了
- What about the Pussy Riot girls? - I briefed them myself.
她们希望你跟佩特罗夫谈这些问题
Here's a list of the issues they want you to discuss with Petrov.
-一切就绪了  -告诉她们我谈了
- We're good to go. - Tell them I did.
请她们共进晚餐真的好吗
Sure it's a good idea to have them at the dinner?
多聪明  她们是异见分子
It's a smart idea. They're dissidents.
肯定会让佩特罗夫头疼
They've been nothing but a pain in Petrov's ass.
他想拍张照就收买她们吗  可以啊
He wants to co-opt them with a photo? Fine.
对他重要的  对我也重要
If it's important to him, it's important to me.
-鲍勃  -总统先生
- Bob. - Mr. President.
得尽快把修正案敲定好
We have to get these amendments out of committee.
把《美就法》递交国会
Get AmWorks on the floor.
也许能通过一两个  七个不可能全过
We might be able to squeeze a couple through, but not all seven.
那就调整资金来源
Then restructure the funding.
一个委员会只递交一份修正案
Shoot for one amendment in one committee.
找财政委员会试试
Try Ways and Means.
一下子申请全款  共和党肯定不同意
The Republicans will never go for a lump sum.
得根据各个委员会职责分割法案
We have to split it up into jurisdictional parts.
我宣布《美国就业法案》时
When I announced America Works,
承诺了一千万就业岗位
I promised ten million jobs.
是不是该降低一下期望
Maybe it's time to lower expectations.
-不行  听我...  -抱歉  先生
- No, look-- - Pardon me, sir.
佩特罗夫总统的车队还有15分钟到
President Petrov's motorcade is 15 out.
-谢谢  -你去吧
- Thank you. - I'll let you go.
鲍勃  还有几分钟  先坐下
Bob, we have a few more minutes. Please sit down.
你今天的事够多了
You have a lot on your plate today.
不如今晚的国宴上接着谈吧
Why don't we pick it up tonight at the state dinner?
很期待呢  总统先生
Looking forward to it, Mr. President.
懦夫的脸什么样
What is the face of a coward?
临阵脱逃了  只能看得见后脑勺
The back of his head as he runs from the battle.
-欢迎  总统先生  -谢谢  总统先生
- Welcome, Mr. President. - Thank you, Mr. President.
第一次来白宫吗
This is your first visit to the White House?
是啊  但你是我经历过的第三任总统了
Yes, yes. But my third president.
我看过你对约旦河谷的提议了
I have reviewed your proposal for the Jordan Valley.
不错
Impressive.
你喜欢吗
So you liked the proposal?
不行
The answer is no.
我不是开玩笑  总统先生
It's not a joke, Mr. President.
我对你的计划没有任何兴趣
I have no interest whatsoever in pursuing your plan.
翻译   somehacker
翻译   肉松富士
翻译   艾瑞卡
翻译   面条打包子
翻译   国士章鱼X
翻译   小饭
时间轴   兜兜兜爹
时间轴   Ans
后期   饿得慌
顾问   老杜
鸣谢   忙成狗的网飞
鸣谢   阿小小海
俄语顾问   西摆
特效   草草
校对   草草
总监   草草
纸牌屋
第三季  第三集
约旦河谷只是树木  我们不能不见森林
The Jordan Valley is the trees instead of the forest.
而这个双边政策  是在疏远我们
And this bilateral approach, it's... alienating.
我跟卡斯皮女士并不总能达成一致
I don't often see eye to eye with Ms. Caspi,
但你们似乎是在要求巴勒斯坦
but it does feel like you're asking the state of Palestine
支持一项我们不能参与商议制定的计划
to support a plan without having a seat at the table.
我们的目标是软化俄罗斯
Well, our goal is to soften Russia,
先让他们作为合作伙伴加入
to bring them in as a partner first--
如果能说服俄国组建联合部队
If we can get the Russians to agree to a joint force,
一起监控约旦河谷  他们会加入的
monitor the valley together, then they're invested.
之后他们就不会阻碍我们...
They won't be a thorn in our side when we move forward--
我们能指望俄罗斯吗
How can we count on the Russians?
你丈夫真认为佩特罗夫信得过吗
Does your husband truly believe he can trust Petrov?
总统很乐观
The president is optimistic.
我们只希望你们愿意考虑
All we ask is that you remain open-minded.
希望你把
I hope you'll convey our
我们的不满直接传达给你丈夫
dissatisfaction directly to your husband.
我一定转达你们的担忧
I'll be sure to share your concerns.
安德伍德大使会跟你们保持联络的
Ambassador Underwood will remain in contact with both of you.
之前不该插你的话
I shouldn't have interrupted you earlier.
会面时  太不应该了
In the meeting. It was out of place,
我该让你说的
and I should have let you do all the talking.
没事的
It's fine.
我知道你对我有怀疑
I know you have doubts about me.
休会任命的事  我们还没谈过
The recess appointment. We haven't discussed it.
-应该谈谈的  -真的没必要
- And we should. - It really isn't necessary.
这的确不合常规
It is an unorthodox dynamic, yes.
你也总归是第一夫人
You will always be the First Lady.
这也是你的飞机  但我们能处理好
This is your plane, after all. But we can work around that.
我知道  但我想告诉你...
Yes, I know, but I want you to know that--
安德伍德夫人  总统来电
Mrs. Underwood, the president is on the line.
怎么样
How'd it go?
-要接通凯茜吗  -不  直接跟我说
- Should we conference Cathy in? - No, just tell me.
有很对反对  他们不满意
A lot of pushback. They aren't happy.
等时机成熟  他们就会同意
Well, they'll get on board when the time comes.
-你那边怎么样  -他说不
- What about you? - He said no.
-这是他嘴里冒出的第一个字  -全盘拒绝吗
- First word out of his mouth. - No to everything?
他可能只是玩心理战
Oh, he might just be playing mind games,
让我自乱脚
trying to throw me off balance,
但他毕竟是克格勃出身
but this is a guy who was brought up through the KGB, after all.
你和凯茜出手得温柔点
We're gonna have to have you and Cathy use the light touch.
我们得软磨硬泡
We need to massage this.
我们接通凯茜吧
Let's include her in this phone call.
不  你直接告诉她  我马上要会面了
No, just tell her. I have to go in soon.
不直接告诉她很不好
It's important we don't bypass her.
好像我们有意不跟她通气  弗兰西斯
If it looks like we're leaving her out of the loop, Francis...
行  接通她
All right, put her on.
我无法形容这对我们团队是多么重要
I can't tell you how much it would mean to the team.
能有您这样履历的专业人士加入
To have your qualifications, your expertise on board.
光是把您的名字摆在网页上就够风光了
Even just having your name on the website.
很感激您这么说  议员先生
I appreciate your saying that, Congressman.
请叫我布拉德  实习生才叫我议员先生
Brad. Please. Congressman's what the interns call me.
行  就叫布拉德
All right. Brad it is.
至于您的头衔  特别顾问行吗
Now as for your title, I was thinking Special Advisor?
-头衔不重要  -随您怎么叫
- Title doesn't matter to me. - You pick what you want.
工作时间您说了算  想来就来  想走就走
And you make your own hours. Come and go as you like.
22万美元一年怎么样
Uh, compensation, would 220 a year work for you?
上限是17.3万
The cap is 173.
另外五万从我的改选资金里拨
Well, the extra 50K would come out of my re-election fund.
只拿最高工资不是亏待了您
I mean, you deserve more than the cap.
您的提议很慷慨
That's a very generous offer.
希望您能付出等价努力
Well, I expect you to earn it.
这次竞选我很想有所作为
I really want to make my mark this session.
-比安德伍德付的还多  -什么
- That's more than Underwood paid me. - I'm sorry?
我当他的幕僚长时  拿最高工资
When I was his chief of staff, I made the cap.
他给的远不到22万
He never came anywhere near 220.
我说过  我觉得您该...
Well, like I said, I think you deserve--
工资太高了  议员先生
It's too much money, Congressman.
我不觉得  但是
Well, I disagree, but,
您想拿少点我不反对
hey, I'm not gonna argue if you want to get paid less.
我说了  这份运输法案
As I was saying, this transpo bill,
能产生很大的影响
we really have an opportunity to make a difference.
女士们  先生们  会面结束
Ladies and gentlemen, the session is over.
请往这边走  谢谢前来
Please, right this way. Thank you for coming.
我听说您最近开始冲浪了
I hear you've recently taken up surfing.
黑海那边有几个地方不错
We have a few spots on the Black Sea.
主要是我能摆姿势拍照
It's mostly so I can pose for the photos.
是  我看到照片了
Yes, I've seen them.
年轻人喜欢
It plays well with the young people.
让他们看到自己的总统有点乐趣很重要
It's important they see their president has some fun,
不会把自己搞得太严肃
doesn't take himself too seriously.
我给你准备了份礼物
I have a gift for you.
抱歉来晚了
I'm sorry for the delay.
希望没让你们等太久
I hope we didn't keep you waiting too long.
可以开始了吗
Shall we?
这是托马斯·吴亲手做的  很有才的美国手艺人
This was handmade by Tomas Vu, a very talented American artist.
一面用激光刻了画  另一面
He laser-etches images on one side, and on the other side...
是披头士的歌词
he puts Beatles lyrics.
回到苏联时期了
Back in the USSR.
这是博物馆藏品  但你还是能用它冲浪
It's a museum piece, but you can still ride it.
你什么来我索契的乡间别墅吧
You should come out to my dacha in Sochi sometime.
我们可以一起冲浪
We'll surf together.
水冷得刺骨  但当地女人很热情
The water is cold as hell, but... the women are very warm.
克莱尔怕是不会乐意
Oh, I'm not sure what Claire would think about that.
带她一起
Well, bring her along.
那里有很多艺术家
It's crawling with artists out there.
说不定她能找到喜欢的
She might find something she likes.
总统先生  我很好奇
Mr. President, I'm intrigued.
你一到美国对我说的第一个字就是"不"
The first thing you say to me is "No" the second you arrive,
紧接着又邀请我去你的乡间别墅
and the next moment you're inviting me to your dacha.
你到底是个什么样的人
Who am I dealing with?
我刚来就说清楚了  你有什么疑惑
I believe I was clear when we first met. What confuses you?
我们的代表团谈这些事谈了好几个月
Our delegations have been discussing these issues for months.
没错  但谈不代表达成一致
Yes, but discussions are not the same as commitment.
我现在告诉你
And, uh, I'm telling you now.
我们不会达成一致
There will be no commitment.
这你打电话就能告诉我了
You could've told me that on the phone.
我以为你邀我来是想弥补对我的侮辱
I assumed you were undoing an insult by having me here.
什么侮辱
What insult is that?
你的前两任都没邀请我来过华盛顿
Two of your predecessors never invited me to Washington.
这次峰会不是走过场
This summit is not just for show.
我希望能朝着和平的目标迈出一大步
I want to make meaningful strides toward peace.
历史告诉我们  中东地区是没救了
The Middle East is hopeless. History tells us that.
我是在给你创造历史的机会
I'm offering you the chance to make history.
我就跟你说实话了
I'll be honest with you,
毕竟你好心好意请我来
because you've been kind enough to invite me to your country.
中东和平  对俄罗斯毫无利益可言
Russia has nothing to gain from peace in the Middle East.
更重要的是  和美国合作也毫无利益
And more importantly, nothing to gain from working with America.
以色列一向不信任我们
Israel has always distrusted us.
你指望这有所改变吗
You expect that to change?
我们希望能慢慢建立信任
We expect to build trust over time.
你们今早和大使们的会面怎么样
How was your meeting with the ambassadors this morning?
阿鲁里大使给我打电话了
Ambassador Aruri called me.
他们有疑虑
They have their doubts,
但我们希望他们能愿意考虑
but we encouraged them to keep an open mind.
他说他十分担忧
He described it as grave concerns.
等我们确定了他们自然会适应...
They will acclimate as soon as we establish--
你丈夫直接向以色列和巴勒斯坦提议了吗
Has your husband made direct overtures to Israel and Palestine?
所有正式通讯
All formal communication
都经由国务院处理
has been handled through the State Department.
但你丈夫不可能认为他们会顺从吧
But your husband can't possibly believe they'll comply.
先生们  为了让谈话进行下去
Gentlemen, for the purposes of these talks,
请你们叫他总统
I'd appreciate it if you refer to him as the president,
而不是"我丈夫"
not as my husband.
当然  大使女士
Of course, Madam Ambassador.
而且你该向杜兰特国务卿发问
And you really should be addressing Secretary Durant.
她比我更能代表总统的意见
She speaks on his behalf more than I do.
抱歉  国务卿女士  请继续吧
Our apologies, Madam Secretary. Please, continue.
我们想把细节梳理完  请翻到12页
We'd like to finish reviewing the specifics, so page 12, please.
总统先生  我们已经在多个方面展开了合作
Mr. President, we're already working together on several fronts:
防核扩散协议  打击恐怖主义  朝鲜
nonproliferation, the War on Terror, North Korea.
为什么中东就偏偏不行呢
I don't see any reason that the Middle East should be any different.
-因为这是美国的计划  -不是那样
- Because it's an American plan. - It's not an American plan.
-我保证条件平等  -保证
- I'm promising equal terms. - Oh, promises.
卡特总统保证双方平等参与
Carter promised equal involvement,
1978年在戴维营军事基地
卡特总统促成埃及与以色列之间
签署了《戴维营协议》
最后签协议的时候却没叫我们
then shut us out of Camp David.
波斯尼亚战争  克林顿也是如此
Clinton did the same with Bosnia.
现在我是总统
I'm the president now.
这次不会那样了
That won't happen this time.
直到18个月之后  你下台
Until 18 months from now, when you are replaced.
我很嫉妒  维克多
I'm jealous, Viktor.
你不用向任何人汇报  没有任何对手
You don't answer to anyone. You have no real opposition.
你也知道大选结果会怎么样
You know exactly how every election is gonna turn out.
美国可不是这样
Well, it's not like that in the United States.
我不竞选  是因为我
I'm not running because I can
能做到总统候选人做不到的事  比如这份提议
do things a candidate can't do, like this proposal.
得了吧  总统先生  你我都知道你会参选的
Please, Mr. President, we both know you'll run.
不过能不能赢  谁知道呢
Now, whether you win... Who knows?
直说吧  你究竟想要什么
Brass tacks. If you could have anything, what would it be?
我没什么想要的
I came with nothing to ask.
你这种人如果没有胃口  是不会赴宴的
Men like you don't show up for dinner without an appetite.
我旅途劳顿  总统先生
It was a long flight, Mr. President.
先谈到这儿吧
How about we stop here for now.
我休息休息眼睛
I rest my eyes a bit and
等精神好点再想想这个提案
put some thought into this with a fresh mind.
没准能想出我要什么
Maybe I'll... think of something I want.
等晚宴的时候再谈
We'll talk more later, at dinner.
可以啊  如果你想这样
Of course, if that's what you prefer.
他知道自己要什么  就是要别人求他
He knows exactly what he wants, but he needs to be wooed.
不过也算有进展
Progress, nonetheless.
不经过"也许"  是没法把"不"变成"好"的
You can't turn a "No" to a "Yes" without a "maybe" in between.
先生们
Gentlemen...
副局长来了
Deputy Director coming through.
奥尔西  跟我来
Orsay? Come with me, please.
我们抓到亚设了
We got Asher.
凌晨两点半  他要吓死了
Two-thirty this morning. He was scared to death.
15分钟之后  他给了我们6TB的压缩文件
By 2:45, he gave us six terabytes of compressed files.
两千五百万美国电话电报公司用户的信息
All 25 million AT&T users.
你的货存错地方了
You hid your goodies with the wrong person.
-不止他一个  -我觉得就他一个
- He wasn't the only one. - I think he was.
我的指控已经撤销了  你没法逮捕我
You can't arrest me for charges that have already been dropped.
放松  没人要逮捕你
Relax. No one's arresting you.
从我手上的报告看
From the reports I've been getting,
你工作一直很出色
you've been doing an excellent job for us.
好好继续干下去  前途无量
If you stay straight, sky's the limit.
接大任务  领导自己的团队
Bigger assignments. Manage your own team.
你知道我也是走投无路才来的
You know I wouldn't be here if I had a choice.
但你现在有选择了
But you do have a choice.
你可以充分利用这第二次机会
You can make the most of this second chance if you want to,
但你得证明你想要这机会
but... you have to prove you want it.
-名字  -我不求别的
- Names. - That's all I've ever wanted.
不行
No.
亚设会供出名字的
Asher's going to give up names.
-他不会那么做的  -或许会
- He wouldn't do that. - He might.
但愿他们不会抖出些
Let's hope none of them tell us
我们还不知道的你的罪行
about anything we didn't charge you for.
你在这里可以有大好未来  嘉文
You have a future here, Gavin.
好了  回去吧
All right. Back to it.
好好工作
Keep up the good work.
我们得去晚宴了
We have to wine and dine.
-要迷倒他们  -他们  还有谁
- Charm them senseless. - Them? Who's the other?
博奇  他压着《美就法》不肯动弹
Birch. He's sitting on AmWorks like his ass is afraid of the sun.
别逼我跟鲍勃聊天
Please don't make me talk to Bob.
你只用负责佩特罗夫  我来对付鲍勃
You just focus on Petrov. I'll deal with Bob.
打扰一下  先生  我们准备好了
Excuse me, sir. We're all set.
佩特罗夫总统在黄色椭圆厅了
President Petrov is in the Yellow Oval.
谢谢  卡莉斯塔
Thank you, Calista.
我可能需要弥补一下凯茜
I think I may need to do some damage control with Cathy.
-为什么  -我一直努力对她恭敬
- Why? - I've been trying to be deferential,
但她可能觉得我是自视高她一等
but I think it's coming off as patronizing.
-本就有这风险  -我知道
- Well, that was the risk. - I know.
她觉得受威胁了吗
Is she feeling threatened?
威胁  不会  可能有点被抢了风头
Threatened, no. Possibly overshadowed.
我的关注度太高
I think I'm getting too much attention
凯茜不跟我一队
and it's tough to be effective
我会举步维艰
when I don't have Cathy on my team,
我可能得讨她欢心
so I may need to win her over.
别忘了今晚的主角应该是谁
Well, let's not forget where the focus is tonight.
我什么时候不能一心二用了
Since when can't I do two things at once?
-你歪了  -什么
- You're crooked. - What?
-准备好去战斗了吗  -是的
- Ready for battle. - Yes.
美利坚合众国副总统  唐纳德·布莱斯
The Vice President of the United States, Donald Blythe.
-总统先生  欢迎  -副总统先生
- Mr. President. Welcome. - Mr. Vice President.
谢谢
Thank you.
佩特罗夫总统  欢迎
President Petrov, welcome.
倍感荣幸
It's a pleasure.
你美极了
You look beautiful.
马马虎虎吧
Oh, it's serviceable.
-你也和往常一样明艳动人  -谢谢
- You look fantastic, as always. - Thank you.
大家的注意力都会在你身上  不是他们
All eyes at the table will be on you, not them.
门多萨参议员  不久就是总统候选人了
Senator Mendoza. Soon to be candidate Mendoza.
这就谣言四起了
The rumor mill begins.
你最开始是跟着里根  对吗
You started with Reagan, no?
他84年竞选团队的一员
Staffed on his '84 campaign.
他办公室里有张里根总统戴牛仔帽的照片
He has a portrait of the Gipper in his office wearing a cowboy hat.
那时男人还有男子气概
When men were men.
鲍勃  我有个想法
Bob, I had a thought.
大卫·布兰切特在军事委员会
Dave Blanchek is on Armed Services and--
我不想让后面的人久等
I don't want to hold up the line.
-总统先生  很荣幸  -移下博奇的位置
- Mr. President, a pleasure. - I want to move Birch.
门多萨换到我边上来
Put Mendoza next to me instead.
艾伦  收拾得挺利索
Alan. You clean up well.
场合需要
Class by association.
-你的女伴呢  -我一个人来的
- Where's your date? - I don't have one.
你想得话  我可以陪你走进去
I can walk you in too, if you'd like.
不了  那不是要毁了你的照片
No. Wouldn't want to ruin the picture.
我们的特殊客人
Ah, our special guests.
很高兴你们能参加晚宴
I'm so delighted you could be with us.
感谢你们能来  总统先生
Thank you so much for coming. Mr. President.
过了这么久才有机会在同一张桌子上坐下
你们在闭门会议时讨论了我们的问题吗
我们讨论了很多事
但我们的担忧呢
我们列出的问题你们谈过了吗
Was anything on our list discussed?
-先照相吧  -好主意
- Why don't we take a photo first? - Good idea. Hm?
门多萨先生
博奇先生
维克多  告诉我  你在恋爱吗
Viktor, tell me. Are you in love?
爱什么的我不知道
I don't know about... love, but...
但我在学习享受离婚的乐趣
I'm learning to enjoy being divorced.
欢迎来到美国
Добро пожаловать!
感谢你们的光临
Спасибо, что вы пришли.
翻译过来就是
Which translates into:
"你好  请别偷银器"
"Howdy, and please don't steal the silverware."
卖弄完了我会说的所有俄语之后
Now that I have exhausted all of the Russian I know,
克莱尔和我想欢迎大家来到白宫
Claire and I would like to welcome all of you to the White House,
很荣幸能在这次历史性的国事访问中
as we host President Petrov
招待佩特罗夫总统
in this historic state visit.
一个世纪前  一个半世纪前
A century ago, a century and a half ago,
法国历史学家  政治家
政治社会学的奠基人
德·托克维尔
de Tocqueville wrote,
对于美国和俄国的看法是这样
in regards to America and Russia, the following:
"他们的出发点和道路不同
"Their point of departure and their paths diverse,
可是  两国似乎都
nevertheless, each seems called
受到了天意的秘密召唤
by some secret desire of providence,
终有一天要将半个世界的命运掌握在自己手里"
to one day hold in their hands the destinies of half the world."
今晚我想做点修改
Well, I'd like to amend that tonight and say,
并不只是半个世界
not just half the world,
全球都指望我们的领导
the entire world looks to us for leadership.
让我们敬佩特罗夫总统
So, to President Petrov,
以及我们两个伟大国家
and all of the great things
精诚合作将创造的美好未来
that our great nations will do together.
-敬总统先生  -说得好
- Mr. President. - Hear, hear!
永远别给法国人机会
Никогда не добрай францусзам.
翻译过来就是  "永远不要相信法国人"
Which is Russian for, "Never trust the French."
总统先生和第一夫人
And thank you to the President
感谢你们热情周到的招待
and First Lady for your grace and hospitality.
比德·托克维尔时代更晚一点
Now, a little more recently than de Tocqueville,
大概三十年前
about, uh, 30 years ago,
米哈伊尔·戈尔巴乔夫来到白宫
Mikhail Gorbachev came to this very House
谈到为两国之间的"不满之冬"划上句号
and talked of an end to our "Winter of discontent."
我认为现在可以说那段寒冬早已结束
I think it's safe to say that that winter seems far gone now.
而现在  在这个醉人的五月夜晚
And here, on this beautiful May evening,
我迎来了这个"迷人之春"
I welcome a "Spring of enchantment."
我们都明白它的魅力从何而来
Now we all know which of you brings the enchantment to the table.
敬您  安德伍德夫人
To you, Mrs. Underwood.
-当然  也敬您的丈夫  -谢谢
- And, of course, your lesser half. - Ah, thank you.
我还想敬这里的另外三位贵宾
Now I'd like to toast three others in this room tonight.
娜迪亚·托伦科尼卡瓦  玛莎·艾柳金纳
Nadya Tolokonnikova, Masha Alyokhina,
和彼得·韦奇洛夫
and Pyotr Verzilov.
我知道我们政见有分歧
Now, I know we had our differences.
但我也知道我们的出发点都一样
But I also know they come from something we all share:
那就是对我们祖国深深的爱
a deep love of our country.
敬你们  也敬俄罗斯
To you. And to Russia.
总统先生  娜迪亚和玛莎想致辞
Mr. President, Nadya and Masha would like to make a toast.
敬俄罗斯总统维克多·佩特罗夫
За Виктора Ивановича Петрова, президента России
对朋友如此义气
который так умеет дружить,
-甚至把半个国家拱手相送  -敬维克多·佩特罗夫
- что подарил своим друзьям полстраны! - To Viktor Petrov,
他对祖国如此忠诚  以至要将半个国家
whose loyalty runs so deep he's given his friends
-拱手让于他人  -他是如此尊敬异己者
- half of the country. - Который так уважает критиков
让他们都进了大牢
что посадил всех критиков в тюрьму!
他开明地接受批评
Who's so open to criticism,
以至于大多批评他的人都已入狱
that most of his critics are in prison.
敬最高统帅维克多·佩特罗夫
За Виктора Пертова, Верховного Главнокомандующего,
他什么都不怕  却害怕同性恋者
которому не страшен никто! Кроме геев.
够了
Хватить!
你们的意思已经很明白了
You made your point.
现在  请坐吧  让我们大家
Now, please, sit and let us all
像真正的俄罗斯人那样开怀畅饮
drink and laugh, like true Russians do.
总统先生
Well, Mr. President,
这就证明你们不要孩子
this is proof why you made the right decision
是多么明智的决定
never to have children.
我的手下跟他们交待过
My staff prepped them.
-他们向我们做了保证  -没关系
- They assured us. - It's nothing.
-我敬佩你的胸襟  -没关系  无需多言
- I admire your grace. - Please. Not another word.
我就知道请暴动小猫不是个好主意
I knew Pussy Riot was a bad idea.
你该去处理
You should go.
不  最好的处理就是不作评论
No. Best thing is not to comment.
否则我们会沦为跟他们一个档次
It lowers us to their level.
喝果汁还是汽水
Juice or soda?
低热量的就行  如果你有的话
Diet something, if you got it.
照片上是谁
Who are they?
我哥哥的孩子
My brother's kids.
挺可爱的
Adorable.
我收到一个工作邀请
I got a job offer.
是吗  哪里
Yeah? Where?
布拉德·帕蒂特的特别顾问
Brad Petite. Special Advisor.
夏威夷的
From Hawaii.
-资浅参议员  -没错
- Junior Congressman? - That's right.
我挺喜欢他  他人不错  很有野心
I like him. He's a good guy. He's ambitious.
他给我开了很高的工资
He offered me a lot of money.
-是吗  -22万年薪
- Yeah? - Two-twenty.
老天
Jesus.
我在白宫永远挣不了这么多
That's more than I would ever make at the White House.
-这工作是你安排的吗  -不是
- You arrange the job? - No.
是总统安排的
Did the President?
-你在说什么啊  -别糊弄我  赛斯
- What are you talking about? - Don't bullshit me, Seth.
我头一次听说这事
This is the first I'm hearing about it.
夏威夷的资深参议员是谁
Who's the Senior Congressman from Hawaii?
拨款委员会主席
Chair of Appropriations.
我认识他  我只是一时想不起来
I know him, I'm just drawing a blank right now.
不是他  是她
It's not him, it's a her.
弗朗辛·谭纳卡  如果你不知道谭纳卡是谁
Francine Tenaka. And if you don't know who Tenaka is,
那你根本不应该认识布拉德·帕蒂特
there's no reason you should know who Brad Petite is,
也不该知道他人怎么样  是否有野心
or that he's ambitious or a good guy.
这个工作机会是你或是总统安排的
This job offer came from you or the President.
我告诉你并非如此
And I'm telling you that it didn't.
我准备拒绝
Well, I'm turning it down.
你转告总统
You tell the President that
只要他需要我  我随时能回去工作
I'm ready to come back whenever he needs me.
我不需要辅助训练
I don't need training wheels.
我需要你今晚上做做博奇的工作
I need you to work on Birch while you're here.
看能不能打听出潜在候选人名单
See if you can get that list of possible candidates.
他被安排在了桌子边上
I don't think putting him down the far end of the table's
好像不太想聊天呢
put him in a very chatty mood.
冷藏  你是在说冷藏吗
Refrigeration. Are you talking about refrigeration?
不是  重新建立桥梁
No. Re-bridge nations.
要在两国之间
We need to re-bridgenate
重新建立桥梁  好增进信任
ourselves so we'll more trust each other.
对吗  对的
Da? Yes.
把修正案递交给国会吧
Let's get these amendments out of committee.
不用全部递交  一部分就行
Not all of them, just some of them.
我要是干涉国会  议长肯定要发飙的
The Speaker would go ballistic if I started meddling in the House.
你可是潜在候选人  他不会轻易跟你翻脸
Not if it means he's going to battle with the presumptive nominee.
他知道得靠谁吃饭
He knows where his bread is buttered.
你休会任命了你老婆  逼我接受
You shove your wife's recess appointment down my throat,
现在还找我帮忙吗
now you want my help?
总要有人担任那个职位
I had to fill the post.
华盛顿哪没有外交专家
And you have a city full of career diplomats.
任命她简直就是打参议院的脸
Her appointment was a slap in the Senate's face.
不要在一项任命上纠结
Let's not get hung up on appointments, all right?
赫克特  你要我签署什么都可以
Hector, whatever you want me to sign, I'll sign.
我不会拿否决要挟你
I will not hold a veto over your head.
你可以随便否决  反正也是帮我们16年的忙
You can veto whatever you want. Just helps our case in 2016.
失陪了
Excuse me.
哪个更醉人  是酒还是克莱尔·安德伍德
Which is more intoxicating, this wine or Claire Underwood?
你经常用这句台词吗
How often do you use that line?
-没你那句用得多  -哪句
- Not as often as you use yours. - Which line is that?
"维克多  你在恋爱吗"
"Viktor, are you in love?"
德斯科托总统说
President Descoteaux told me
他来的时候你也问了这句话
you asked him the same thing when he was here.
那晚我丈夫祝酒的时候
I believe my husband quoted
好像引用了俄国作家的话
a Russian author the night he gave that toast.
-我猜猜  托尔斯泰吗  -普希金
- Don't say, uh... Tolstoy? - Pushkin.
"升华友谊的谎言
"A deception that elevates us
要好过一堆无用的事实"
is dearer than a host of low truths."
他才没那么说
He didn't make that toast.
-是没有  -没有
- No, he didn't. - No, no.
说实话  你是真了解普希金
Tell me, do you actually know your Pushkin,
还是知道我来才研究的
or did you just study up before I arrived?
重要吗
Does it really matter?
他就是这么做事吗
So, this is what he does?
让你来诱惑别人
He leaves the seduction to you.
是不是有个词来着
Isn't there a... a word for that in English?
-什么词  -拉皮条  是吗
- For what? - "Pimping," Yes?
他在给你拉皮条
He's pimping you out.
你真有风度
How charming you are.
谢谢
Thank you.
据我的人说  你做第一夫人
And you make a much better First Lady than ambassador,
比作大使强多了
from what my people tell me.
开玩笑的
Only teasing.
再来点酒  给大使的
More wine... for the ambassador.
请吧
Please.
我得回去一会儿
I'm gonna have to go in a couple minutes.
总统先生  给您的礼物
Mr. President, my gift for you.
世上最好的伏特加
Best vodka in the world.
莫斯科特供
Osobaya Sayanskaya.
纯金瓶
Solid gold.
每瓶75万美元
Each one of these bottles is 750,000.
来敬杯酒
Now, a toast.
敬友谊  敬美食
To friendship, to good food,
敬列夫·托尔斯泰的名言
and to Leo Tolstoy, who said,
"想要快乐  随心而动"
"If you want to be happy, be."
干杯
Drink!
然后闻一下面包
Now... you sniff your bread.
说"好"
Say "ну".
好
ну!
再吹吹口哨
Then whistle.
闻一下袖子
Sniff your sleeve.
然后吃腌黄瓜
And... eat your pickle. -
我们为什么要这么做呢
Now, why we do all this?
谁也不知道
No one knows.
再来一杯
Again!
算了  总统先生
Oh, no. Now, Mr. President.
你  副总统先生
Now, you, Mr. Vice President.
敬酒词
A toast!
敬我们两国之间
Uh, to, uh... further cooperation
进一步的合作  还有继续...
between our two countries and, uh... continued... uh...
管他的  喝
Oh, hell. Here's how!
再来
Again!
到你了  安德伍德夫人
Now, you... Mrs. Underwood.
敬佩特罗夫总统和他的
To President Petrov and his...
小腌黄瓜
little pickle.
喝
Drink!
再来
Again!
抗议风头压过佩特罗夫国宴
你说地点  我定时间
吃晚餐吗
发送至  嘉·奥尔西
*只有一阵节奏*
*They only had the rhythm so*
30分钟
*随之摇摆左右*
*They started swaying to and fro*
*不知该如何搭配旋律*
*They didn't know just what to use*
*这就是蓝调*
*This is how the blues*
*真正的起源*
*Really began*
总统先生  跟我合唱一首
Mr. President, Why don't you come up and join me?
不了  不了
Oh, no, no, no.
-来吧  -是你在演唱
- Come on. - It's your show.
我知道你会唱歌  我知道你能唱
I know you can sing. I know you can sing.
来吧
Come on.
那好  我大概知道这首歌
All right, well, I almost... I almost know this song.
我不是很确定  唱到哪了
I'm not so sure. Uh, how's it go now?
他们听到风吹
They heard the breeze.
*他们听到风吹*
*They heard the breeze*
*从林中吹过*
*Through the trees*
*唱着奇怪的曲调*
*Singin' weird melodies*
*他们管这叫*
*And they made that*
*蓝调的起源*
*The start of the blues*
*然后他们培养*
*And then they nursed it*
*他们排练*
*And they rehearsed it*
*他们放出消息*
*And they they gave out the news*
*说是南国*
*That the Southland*
*孕育了蓝调之乐*
*Gave birth to the blues*
*说是南国*
*That the Southland*
*孕育了蓝调之乐*
*Gave birth to the blues*
我只会唱这些
That's all I have.
好极了  好极了  总统先生
Beautiful. Beautiful, Mr. President.
好了  辛科蒂先生
Now... now, Mr. Cincotti,
这首你可能不知道
uh, you might not know this one.
但很好弹
But, um... it's easy to follow.
给我个C调
You have a C for me?
Коробейники  货郎
*噢  装满了我的货篮*
*Ой, полным-полна моя коробушка*
*装满了棉布和织锦*
*Есть и ситец, и парча*
*来吧  我心爱的姑娘*
*Пожалей, моя зазнобушка*
你拿否决权跟门多萨做交易了吗
You offered vetoes for sale to Mendoze?
*用你有力的的肩膀*
*Молодецкого плеча*
鲍勃  总统在唱歌呢
Bob, shh... the president's singing.
这就是你把他安排在旁边的原因吗
Is that why you sat him next to you?
*来吧  我心爱的姑娘*
*Пожалей, моя зазнобушка*
鲍勃  你说了  共和党掌控着国会
Bob, as you said, the Republicans control Congress.
*用你有力的的肩膀*
*Молодецкого плеча*
博奇那边有进展吗
Any luck with Birch?
还没  我会继续尝试
No list yet. I'll keep working him.
库克医生呢
Where's Dr. Cooke?
接到电话有场手术要赶去做
He got called away to surgery.
留给斯维特拉吧
Save it for Svetla.
她不叫这个
That's not her name.
她看着像斯维特拉
She looks like a Svetla.
*噘起你那红红的唇*
*Подставляй-ка губки алые*
*紧紧挨着我身边*
*Ближе к молодцу садись*
*我可下了不小的本钱*
*Цены сам платил я не малые*
*你可不要压价钱*
*Не торгуйся, не скупись*
*噘起你那红红的唇*
*Подставляй-ка губки алые*
*紧紧挨着我身边*
*Ближе к молодцу садись*
*噘起你那红红的唇*
*Подставляй-ка губки алые*
*紧紧挨着我身边*
*Ближе к молодцу садись*
晚宴到现在该收尾了
Well, I don't think we can end the evening on a higher note,
我想感谢你们所有人的到来
so I want to thank you all for coming,
一块唱歌跳舞  还喝伏特加
for the singing and the dancing and the vodka.
尤其是我的朋友  彼得·辛科蒂
But most especially to my friend, Peter Cincotti.
谢谢你
Thank you.
大老远来到白宫
Coming all the way here to the White House.
谢谢  谢谢你们带来的精彩一晚
Thank you. Thank you! Thank you for a wonderful evening.
精彩绝伦  感谢你  辛科蒂先生
Wonderful. And thank you to you, Mr. Cincotti.
谢谢  谢谢
Thank you. Thank you.
您的车队准备好了  总统先生
Your motorcade is ready, Mr. President.
我送你出去
I'll walk you out.
但我想先带你看样东西  跟我来
But first, I want to show you something. Come with me.
-我们马上来  卡莉斯塔  -好的  先生
- We'll be right down, Calista. - Yes, sir.
我要是帮你换到别的机构去呢
What if I get you transferred? To some other agency.
这跟我在哪工作没关系  他会想出法子的
It doesn't matter who I work for. He'll find a way.
你很想留在这里吗
How much do you care about staying here?
-什么  特区吗  -这个国家
- What, DC? - In this country.
他们把我护照锁了
I'd have been long gone if
要不然我早跑了
they didn't put a travel lock on my passport.
那就解锁啊
So let's unlock it.
你能办到吗  要是我给你你想要的
Is that something you can do? If I get you what you want?
我需要知道她具体在哪
I need to know exactly where she is.
不要告诉我哪个州还是哪个市  我要地址
Not a state. Not a city. An address.
我要是用局里的软件查被抓包了
If I use the Bureau's software and get caught,
我会把你的名字抖出来
I'll give them your name.
我理解
I understand.
好吧
All right.
把你知道她的事全告诉我
Tell me everything you know about her.
晚安
Good night.
-深夜小酌一杯  -太晚了
- How about a night cap? - Oh, it's late.
大学之后就没喝过那么多伏特加了
And I haven't had that much vodka since college.
杜兰大学  是吗
Tulane, right?
别人是这么说的  我都记不清了
So they tell me. It's all a bit of a blur.
你在学校喝什么  飓风鸡尾酒吗
What did you drink in school? Hurricanes?
我们不是野蛮人  威士忌不加冰
Oh, we weren't barbarians. Scotch, no ice.
两杯芝华士  不加冰
Two Chivas, neat.
古巴货  偷运进来的
Cubans. Smuggled in.
想着你会喜欢这其中的讽刺意味
I thought you might appreciate the irony.
没错
I do.
这通到哪
And where does this lead?
地下室入口
Basement entrance.
尼克松的孩子从这儿带约会对象进来
The Nixon kids would bring their dates up this way.
肯尼迪估计也用来干过类似的事
Kennedy probably used it for similar reasons.
要知道  我现在离婚了
Well, you know, now that I'm divorced,
我用不着偷偷带人进克里姆林宫
I don't have to sneak anyone in and out of the palace.
他们能从正门光明正大地进来
They can come through the front door. With some dignity.
拿"光明正大"来形容情妇有点过了吧
Well, dignity's a bit overrated for a mistress, don't you think?
有些女人  比如你妻子那样的
You know, a woman like your wife, for example,
绝对值得人费这个事
would certainly make it worthwhile.
你会见过的总统的老婆你都亲吗
Do you kiss the wife of every president you meet?
可不是每位总统的老婆都像你妻子那么美
Not every president's wife looks like yours.
我真想立马把他从楼梯上推下去摔死再焚尸
I'd push him down the stairs and light his broken body on fire
眼看着他烧成灰
just to watch it burn,
只可惜那会引发世界大战
if it wouldn't start a world war.
-我能下去看看吗  -请便
- May I? - Of course.
你觉得他们能回心转意吗
Well, do you think they'll ever come around?
我可说不准
Oh, I don't know.
肯定还要开更多峰会  派国会代表团
There'll be more summits, a hundred CoDels.
像打乒乓那样来回扯好几个月
They'll ping-pong back and forth for months
佩特罗夫才会表明心意
before Petrov shows his hand.
-怎么了  -没什么
- What? - Nothing.
告诉我吧
Tell me.
我只是在想象布格考夫打乒乓的样子
I was just picturing Bugakov playing ping-pong.
布加耶夫
Bugayev?
想想他玩啤酒乒乓球的样子吧
Imagine him playing beer pong.
那这谈判也不用谈了
Then these negotiations would be over.
我可是ΔΦ联谊会的啤酒乒乓赛冠军
You are looking at the Delta Phi beer pong champion.
-不是吧  -是真的
- No. - Yes.
大二大三蝉联两届
Both sophomore and junior years.
大四怎么没赢
And what happened senior year?
我得备考法学院了
Well, I had to start studying for law school.
我虽然说不上是冠军
Well, I wasn't... a champion.
-不过玩得也不赖  -你
- I wasn't too bad, though. - You?
-咱俩该玩两局  -什么
- I think we should play. - What?
-你开玩笑的吧  -不好意思
- Oh, you can't be serious. - Excuse me?
能否去跟内务人员要几个乒乓球来
Can you ask housekeeping to bring us some ping-pong balls, please?
我得回家了
I have got to go home.
我们就按哈佛的规矩来
We'll be playing by Harvard rules.
他们的无畏值得尊敬
You have to admire their fearlessness.
让这些女人绝育就好了
布加耶夫
不过他们不会理解的  对不对
None of them understand, do they?
统治需要的决断
What it takes to govern.
他们大喊大叫  上蹿下跳
They scream and yell and stomp their feet,
但要真让他们坐在我们的位子上
but if they had to spend just one day in our shoes,
体会一下我们肩上的担子
the weight we carry on our shoulders...
比如说  中东
Like, um... the Middle East?
我知道我们躲到这里抽烟是为什么
Oh, I know why we're here, smoking our cigars.
-怎么样  -你不会喜欢我的回答的
- And? - You're not going to like it.
中了
Yes!
快干了
Drink up.
好  为了哈佛
Okay. For the Crimson.
可恶
Damn!
神技仍在
Yes! I still got it.
你不用喝光了的
You don't have to drink that.
多谢你手下留情
I accept your mercy.
趁你没要求重赛  我赶紧回家吧
And I am going to leave before you challenge me to a rematch.
你都不给我在自己家里赢一回的机会吗
You're not even gonna give me a shot at winning in my own house?
外交界第一法则  见好就收
First rule of diplomacy: stop while you're ahead,
佩特罗夫敬第三杯伏特加时
which is what I should've done,
我也该见好就收的
after that third vodka of Petrov's.
你怎么看这个人
What do you think of him?
佩特罗夫吗  我不知道
Petrov? I don't know.
跟他聊了一晚上的人是你啊
You were the one who talked to him all night.
礼仪要求  我没得选
Well, I didn't have much of a choice.
看来你不喜欢他
So, not a fan?
我认为他很聪明  独具魅力
I think he's very intelligent. And he has a charm.
他亲你  有点过分了
That kiss was... too much.
不  他那是非常过分
No, that's just pushing buttons.
俄国人就喜欢这么惹别人
The Russians love to do that.
晚安
Good night.
我觉得不能相信他  凯茜
I don't think he's to be trusted, Cathy.
尤其是今晚之后  让我不禁思考
Especially after tonight. And it made me think...
继续说
Go on.
这让我重新考虑了弗兰西斯的计划
It made me wonder about Francis' plan.
我认为与佩特罗夫合作未必是好主意
I'm not sure that it's a good idea to be partnered with Petrov.
而且我们还破坏了与以色列和巴勒斯坦的关系
In the meantime, we alienate Israel and Palestine.
私下里告诉你  我也同意
Well... between you and me, I agree.
过来坐
Sit with me.
那你想采取什么不同的办法呢
What would you do differently?
这个
Well...
如果最终目标是向约旦河谷派军的话
If the goal is to get troops into the Jordan Valley,
达到目标的办法可不止一种
well, then there's more than one way to skin that cat.
多国部队吗
A multinational force?
我倾向通过联合国
I would go through the UN.
维和部队吗
Peacekeeping?
但俄罗斯会否决的
You wouldn't get past Russia's veto.
也许有个办法  但是...
There might be a way, but...
那样你就有很重的任务了
you'd have a lot of responsibility on your shoulders.
如果你能指点我  我相信我能处理好
Well, if you can give me guidance, I'm sure I can handle it.
以前有联合维和决议案的先例
There is precedent with the Uniting for Peace Resolution.
我们就是借这个  绕过苏俄发动了朝鲜战争
We used it to get around the Russians for the Korean War.
-全部吗  -从波兰到英国
- The whole thing? - From Poland to the UK.
我希望整个导弹防御系统都拆除
I want the entire missile defense system gone.
你知道那是为了防御朝鲜和伊朗
You know that's there to defend against North Korea, against Iran.
但比起朝鲜伊朗  却离我国更近
And far closer to my borders than theirs.
我只是希望你派几千部队进入约旦河谷
I'm asking for a few thousand troops in the Jordan Valley.
你却要求我废除欧洲的防御系统
You're asking me to dismantle Europe's defense system.
你真正的要求是让美国部队
What you're really asking for is American forces
进入高加索南部
just south of the Caucasus.
你肯定已经想好了战略规划
You must have a strategic play in mind.
这是为了地区稳定
This is about stability in the region.
你是想巩固在这个地区的地位吧
You're trying to consolidate your foothold in the region.
黑海  哈萨克斯坦  车臣  克里米亚
The Black Sea, Kazakhstan, Chechnya, Crimea.
拜托  别扯什么和平来侮辱我了
So, please... don't insult me with peace.
无论你的战略目标是什么
Whatever your strategic goals may be,
导弹防御系统是我的
the missile defense system is mine.
维克多  我邀请你来华盛顿的目的很纯粹
Viktor, I invited you to Washington with pure intentions,
就是为了我们能一起进餐  学习信任对方
so that we could break bread and learn to trust one another.
弗兰西斯  一顿美妙的晚餐
Francis, I don't get softened up
和与美丽的女士共舞不会让我心软的
by a nice dinner and dancing with a beautiful woman.
你问我想要什么
You asked me what I want.
我告诉你了
Well... I told you.
这样吧
I'll tell you what.
现在我要去睡会儿了
It's my turn to get some sleep.
等头脑清醒点再处理这些事吧
Let's attack all this with a fresh mind.
我们还没抽完雪茄呢
We've barely smoked our cigars.
我们不是那种无节制的人  对吧
We're not men of excess, though, are we?
不是吗
Aren't we?
不是
No, no.
不  你说得对
No, you're right.
这一晚上抽得够多了
Enough smoke for one evening.
你打算怎么办
What are you going to do?
不知道
I don't know.
想办法与他妥协吧
Try to meet him halfway.
凯茜和我聊了一会儿
Cathy and I were talking.
也许以色列人和巴勒斯坦人是对的
Maybe the Israelis and the Palestinians are right.
我们应该考虑从他们下手
We should consider starting with them.
利用联合国向俄罗斯施压
Use the United Nations to put pressure on Russia.
-怎么施压  -联合维和
- How? - Uniting for Peace.
让联合国大会推翻
General Assembly overrides
俄罗斯在安理会投的否决票
a Russian veto in the Security Council.
即便成功  也只会激怒他们
Well, that'll just antagonize them even if it works.
何况不可能成功
And it won't.
也许呢  凯茜似乎认为会成功
Well, it might work. Cathy seems to think it could.
我以为你对这计划有信心
I thought you believed in this plan.
我们只是在考虑别的选择
We were just... brainstorming alternatives.
我付出了这么多努力  怎么能前功尽弃
Well, I've worked too hard on it just to abandon it.
好吧  你知道怎么最好
Okay, you know best.
你介意吗
Do you mind?
什么
What?
关灯
The light.
弗兰西斯
Francis.
他是个恶棍
He's a thug.
很聪明  但也还是个恶棍
Smart, but he's still a thug.
别向他屈服
Don't cower to him.
在我的家乡
Where I come from,
我们会把生鸡蛋放进番茄汁里  然后喝掉
we drop a raw egg into some tomato juice and drink that.
还好我不来自你的家乡
Luckily, I don't come from there.
那份工作很适合道格
That's a perfect job for Doug.
真不明白他为什么拒绝
I can't imagine why he'd turn it down.
他觉得是我们在背后安排的
He thinks we were behind it.
我告诉他并没有  但恐怕他不相信我
I told him we weren't, but I don't think he believes me.
说他不需要辅助训练
Said he doesn't need training wheels.
我要你继续偶尔去看看他
Well, I want you to still stop in from time to time and see him.
是  先生
Yes, sir.
国防部长来了吗  让他进来
Is the Secretary of Defense here? Send him in.
-总统先生  -我们没多少时间
- Mr. President. - We don't have much time.
佩特罗夫90分钟后到  我们得谈欧洲的情况
Petrov gets here in 90 minutes. We need to talk Europe.
答案是可以
The answer is yes.
可以接受你的部分但并非全部要求
To some, not all, of what you asked.
好吧
I see.
我准备对导弹防御系统进行大规模削减
I'm prepared to scale back significantly.
我得先跟我的团队及我们的北约同盟国商量下
Now, I have to speak to my team first and my allies in NATO,
但我相信我们可以在波兰和捷克共和国
but I'm confident that we can do something meaningful
作出重要调整
in Poland and the Czech Republic.
我们双方可以就细节做进一步协商
Now, our people can work out the specifics.
但无论我们达成怎样的共识
And whatever it is we decide and agree on,
都不能让公众知晓
the public cannot know.
我醒来时满嘴都是昨晚抽过的雪茄味
I woke up with the taste of those cigars in my mouth.
让我想到了古巴导弹危机和肯尼迪
Thinking of Cuba and Kennedy.
古巴导弹危机时
美国最终从土耳其撤军
比苏联晚一些  而且是秘密撤军
表面上来看是这场危机的胜利者
我可不会像赫鲁晓夫
I won't be humiliated the way
在土耳其导弹问题上那样被羞辱
Khrushchev was with Turkey.
你不能将我的提议
Well, you can't possibly compare
与当时的事件相提并论
what I'm proposing to what happened then.
只有你同意对外宣布
I can only consider a partial scale-back
我才会接受部分削减
if you announce it.
这场新闻发布会是关于约旦河谷问题
This press conference is about the Jordan Valley.
调整导弹防御系统的重点是削减
The most important thing about the missiles is the scale-back,
不是公关
not the PR.
我的人民需要知道我不是空手而归
My people would know I walked away with something.
而且对外宣布后  我就能逼你信守诺言
And, by announcing it, I can keep you to your word.
我可是做出了相当大的让步  维克多
I am more than meeting you halfway, Viktor.
你知道苏联解体最大快人心之处是什么吗
You know what the best part of the Fall of the Soviet Union was?
是汽车
The cars.
你坐过拉达牌汽车吗
Have you ever been in, um... a Lada?
拉达  没有
Lada? No, I haven't.
没有吗  那是世上最烂的车
No? Oh. It's the worst car ever built.
很小  很袖珍的一辆车
Tiny, little thing, you know.
车开过坑颠一下  你的头就会撞到车顶
Your head would hit the ceiling when you hit a pothole.
暖气永远不制热
And the heat never worked.
还没有空调
And no air conditioning.
大夏天皮肤都要粘到座位上
You know, your skin would stick to the seats in the summer.
简直是可移动的棺材
It was a coffin on wheels.
但苏联解体后  就能买到雷克萨斯
But then, after the Fall, we got the Lexus.
有空调  自动车窗
Temperature control. Automatic windows.
而且空间很大
And so much room.
我第一次上我前妻  就是在一辆雷克萨斯里
First time I fucked my ex-wife, in a Lexus.
在拉达里你想都不要想
You could never do that in a Lada.
空间根本不够
No space.
现在情况是这样  总统先生
You see, Mr. President.
我想要雷克萨斯
I want the Lexus.
你却向我推销拉达
And you're trying to sell me a Lada.
我去让你的车队来接你
I'll have them bring your motorcade around.
但还有新闻发布会
But the... press conference.
对啊
Right!
我忘得一干二净
I'd completely forgotten.
不过今天不做新闻发布会也不要紧
But I think we're gonna be okay without one today.
回程一路顺风  总统先生
Have a safe journey home, Mr. President.
多谢你的款待  总统先生
Thank you for your hospitality, Mr. President.
给我接国务卿
Give me the Secretary of State.
总统将单独发表讲话
The President will be speaking alone.
不举行联合新闻发布会
No joint conference.
总统很快就来
The President will be out shortly.
昨晚  我有幸在白宫招待了
Last night, I had the pleasure of hosting
几位非常尊贵的宾客
some very special guests here at the White House.
几位真正的俄罗斯爱国者
True Russian patriots
他们展现了他们国家最优良的美德
who exhibit the very best that their country has to offer.
他们的名字是  娜迪亚·托伦科尼卡瓦
Their names: Nadya Tolokonnikova,
玛莎·艾柳金纳和彼得·韦奇洛夫
Masha Alyokhina and Pyotr Verzilov.
你们应该已经知道
As you're all aware,
他们敢于挑战佩特罗夫总统
they stood up to President Petrov,
并强迫他倾听他不愿听到的真相
and forced him to listen to the truths that he didn't want to hear.
这令我深受震撼
And, well, that had a profound effect on me.
因为这让我意识到
Because it made me realize
我也要勇于与他抗衡
that I need to stand up to him as well.
我们的国家也一样
As does our country.
我邀请总统来访
When I invited the President here,
是旨在结交盟友
I set out hoping to find a partner.
但佩特罗夫总统的要求让我明白
But the demands that President Petrov made proves to me
和平并非他的第一诉求
that peace is not a priority for him.
和平不该通过买卖取得
Peace should not have to be bought.
和平本就该足矣
Peace should be its own reward,
不论他是否是我们的盟友
and we will achieve it,
我们终会迎来和平
with or without him.
非常感谢
Thank you very much.
你知道怎样能绕过俄国
You have thoughts on how to bypass Russia.
就是要让俄国在联合国安理会的否决票无效
The idea is to negate Russia's veto in the Security Council.
我会让大使向您介绍我们的想法
I'll let the Ambassador tell you what we have in mind.
刚上任时  奥巴马渴望同俄罗斯进行合作
2009年奥巴马派遣国务卿希拉里到日内瓦会见俄罗斯外长拉夫罗夫
希拉里特意携带了一个具有象征性的红色按钮
称要同俄罗斯"重置"外交关系
作为一种友好姿态
美国主动终止了在捷克和波兰境内设置导弹防御系统的计划
然而时间证明
奥巴马和希拉里"重置外交关系"的努力并没有获得克里姆林宫的认可
白宫伸出的橄榄枝并没有收获合作与和平
美国前中情局情报员斯诺登向世界泄露大量美国军事机密后
到俄罗斯寻求庇护  得到普京收容
被媒体解读为打在奥巴马脸上的一记耳光
2014年  随着克里米亚和乌克兰局势的恶化
美国政府更是发现俄国不仅没有同美国进行合作的意愿
而且在欧洲事务上几乎是一意孤行  唯我独尊
但是面对克里米亚和乌克兰危机
白宫除了联合欧洲盟国进行经济制裁
并没有其它更有效的办法制约普京
奥巴马因此也在美国国内招致很大非议
在过去的一年中  美国多个机构的民调结果都显示
美国多数民众对奥巴马处理外交
尤其是乌克兰事务的能力表示信心不足